Guide to the Vietnamese American Heritage Foundation oral history interviews collection, 2011 MS 647
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Vietnamese American Heritage Foundation oral history interview collection
2011
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Vietnamese American Heritage Foundation
MS 647
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes and digital objects)
This is a collection of oral history interviews conducted by the Vietnamese American Heritage Foundation, featuring audio recordings and transcripts of interviews with Vietnamese Americans living in and near Houston, Texas. These interviews are online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/79696.
Biographical / Historical
The Vietnamese American Heritage Foundation (http://www.vietnameseamerican.org/) conducted a series of oral history interviews in 2011 as a national project called "500 Oral Histories Project" in the U.S. These interviews have been donated to universities in groups by the location where the interviews took place. The interviews in this collection largely took place in Houston, Texas.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of video interviews dating from 2011 and conducted by the Vietnamese American Heritage Foundation. These interviewees are Texas-based, and form part of the national 500 Oral Histories Project conducted by the Vietnamese Heritage Foundation. These interviews are online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/79696. Most are in Vietnamese, although some are in English. Transcripts for the Vietnamese language interviews were created by Mr. Hieu Do in Vietnam, and have not been verified by a second reader.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was donated by the Vietnamese American Heritage Foundation via Ms. Nancy Bui in 2012.
Index Terms
Subjects
Women; Emigration and immigration; Vietnamese Americans -- Texas -- Houston; Asian Americans; Politics and government; War
Document Types
transcripts; audiotapes; digital audio formats; Oral histories
Subjects (Corporations)
Vietnamese American Heritage Foundation
- Series I: Vietnamese American Heritage Foundation video interviews, 2011
  - An Phong video oral history, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ban Vu video oral history interview, 2011-03-06 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bui Dang Khoa video oral history (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bui Dang Trinh video oral history interview, 2011-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chuong Khuat video oral history interview, 2011-03-05 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dang Quoc Viet video oral history interview, 2011-03-07 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dang Xuan Ngo video oral history, 2011-03-03 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dao Vinh Tuan video oral history, 2011-03-05 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Do Lao video oral history, 2011-03-07 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Doan Quoc Sy video oral history interview, 2011-03-02 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Doan Thi Hanh Dao video oral history interview, 2011-02-28 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Duong Au Oanh video oral history interview, 2011-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Duong Phuc video oral history, 2011-03-04 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Duong Phuoc Tan video oral history interview, 2011-02-28 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Grandmaster Van Binh video oral history interview, 2011-02-27 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ha Ngoc Cu video oral history, 2011-03-05 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hoang Bach video oral history, 2011-03-04 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hoang Ngoc Giao video oral history, 2011-03-05 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Hoang Van Minh video oral history interview, 2011-02-28 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Hoang, Kathy Khanh Han video oral history, 2011-03-05 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hubert Vo video oral history, 2011-03-05 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Huynh Cong Tu and female relative video oral history, 2011-02-27 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Jackie Tran video oral history interview, 2011-03-05 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Jennifer Nguyá video oral history interview, 2011-03-06 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - La Huy Anh video oral history and family documents, 2011-03-03 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - La Huy Quy video oral history, 2011-03-03 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Le Dinh Chau video oral history interview, 2011-03-06 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Le Dinh Cuong video oral history interview, 2011-03-02 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Le Huong Stephen video oral history interview and documents, 2011-02-28 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Le Huu Cu video oral history (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Le Phat Minh video oral history (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Scope and Contents
    Also includes family photos.
  - Le Thi Thu Cuc video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Mui Quy Bong video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Nghiem Nguyá video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Nguyá Anh Lan video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Nguyá Cong Bang video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Nguyá Gia Tuong video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Nguyá Son Lam video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Nguyá Thi Nha video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Nguyá Tuy Ngoc video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Nguyen Cao Binh oral history (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Nguyen Chi Thiep video oral history (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Nguyen Chinh Ket video oral history (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Nguyen Cong Anh Tuan oral history interview, 2011-02-28 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Nguyen Cuong video oral history (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Includes documents related to Bronze Star Medal awarded by U.S.A., 1971
  - Nguyen De video oral history interview, 2011-03-02 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Nguyen Duc Tue video oral history interview, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Nguyen Huong Loan video oral history interview, 2011-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Nguyen Manh An Dan video oral history interview, 2011-03-02 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Nguyen Nga Dung Jane video oral history interview, 2011-02-27 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Nguyen Ngoc Quyet video oral history interview, 2011-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Nguyen Nhung video oral history (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Nguyen Quae Binh video oral history (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Nguyen Quoc Cuong video oral history interview, 2011-03-07 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Nguyen Tan Tri video oral history interview, 2011-03-02 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Includes newsclippings.
  - Nguyen Thi Linh video oral history interview, 2011-02-28 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Nguyen Thu Tien video oral history (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Nguyen Thuong Kham Thien video oral history (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Nguyen Tran video oral history (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Nguyen Tu Chung video oral history interview, 2011-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Nguyen Van Nam video oral history interview, 2011-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Nguyen Van Nhu video oral history interview, 2011-03-07 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Nong Duy Truong video oral history (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Pham Ba Hoa video oral history (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Pham Diem Huong video oral history interview, 2011-02-27 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Pham Duc Nhi video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Pham Ngoc Hai video oral history interview, 2011-03-03 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Pham Quang Tan video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Pham Tam video oral history, 2011-02-28 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Pham Thanh Tan video oral history (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Pham Tuyet Mai video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Steven Dieu video oral history interview, 2011-03-03 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Ta Quynh Hoan video oral history interview, 2011-02-27 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Thien Y Nguyen Van Thang video oral history (Box 1, Folder 74)
    Includes personal documents.
  - Tran Bang Thach video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Tran Hien video oral history (Box 1, Folder 76)
    Includes additional personal photos.
  - Tran Khanh Liem video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Tran Ngoc Tu video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Tran Van Tien video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Tran Van Thuan video oral history interview, 2011-03-02 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    Also includes personal documents.
  - Trinh Kim Duyen video oral history interview, 2011-03-03 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Truong Nhu Phung video oral history interview, 2011-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Van Dinh Mai video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Vo My Le video oral history interview, 2011-02-27 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Vu Kim Yen video oral history interview (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Vu Phuong Anh video oral history (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Vu Thanh Thuy video oral history interview, 2011-03-03 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - William Tran video oral history (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Original donation of born digital content (external hard drive) (Box 2)